{
    "id": "5b2600e61db2443594ea746388f375c0",
    "title": "Report the following statements",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "cdd187c241034f4aa37e974df057cbe1",
            "title": "Reported Speech Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "My mother said, ‘You are the laziest boy I have ever seen.’ / My mother said that I ........................................ the laziest boy she had ever seen.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "am",
                        "was",
                        "had been"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He told me, ‘I don’t like your hairstyle.’ / He told me that he ................................... my hairstyle.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "doesn't like",
                        "didn't like",
                        "hadn't liked"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Martin said, ‘If my father gives me the permission, I will go to Singapore.’ / Martin said that if his father .................................................. him the permission, he would go to Singapore.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "give",
                        "gave",
                        "had given"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "‘I will show you how to do it,’ said the father to his son. / The father told his son that he ............................................. him how to do it.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "showed",
                        "will show",
                        "would show"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "‘I have come to borrow a book from the library,’ the boy said. / The boy said that he ....................................... to borrow a book from the library.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "came",
                        "has come",
                        "had come"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "‘I am going to the US,’ he says. / He says that he .......................................... to the US.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "went",
                        "was going",
                        "is going"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "‘I want to see the house before I buy it,’ he told the agent. / He told the agent that he ............................................ to see the house before he bought it.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "wants",
                        "wanted",
                        "had wanted"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "‘You must change your wet clothes,’ my mother said. / My mother told me that I .................................................. change my wet clothes.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "must",
                        "have to",
                        "had to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "‘We needn’t tell her,’ he said. / He said that they .................................... to tell her.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "don't need",
                        "didn't need",
                        "wouldn't need"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "‘No one can say what will happen next,’ the speaker said. / The speaker said that no one ........................................... what would happen next.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "can say",
                        "could say"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}